[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following organizations is the OLDEST?",
        "a": "the World Meteorological Association",
        "b": "the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme",
        "c": "the World Climate Research Programme",
        "d": "the Global Atmospheric Research Program",
        "e": "the International Council for Science",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who proposed a systematic study of global geophysical activities in the 1950s?",
        "a": "James Hutton",
        "b": "Charles David Keeling",
        "c": "Marie Tharp",
        "d": "Lloyd Berkner",
        "e": "Charles Richter",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was the International GeoPhysical Year significant?",
        "a": "It marked the beginning of a prolonged drought.",
        "b": "It saw the highest ever recorded levels of carbon emissions.",
        "c": "It saw a dramatic increase in global temperatures.",
        "d": "It marked a high point in the sunspot cycle.",
        "e": "It witnessed the onset of a severe El Niño event.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "The IGY united scientists from all of the following subjects EXCEPT",
        "a": "meteorology",
        "b": "geomagnetism",
        "c": "gravity",
        "d": "oceanography",
        "e": "botany",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which greenhouse gas did Charles David Keeling study?",
        "a": "ozone",
        "b": "ammonia",
        "c": "methane",
        "d": "carbon dioxide",
        "e": "nitrous oxide",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which climatic process did scientists begin to understand in the 1950s?",
        "a": "how solar radiation interacts with the Earth’s atmosphere",
        "b": "how ocean currents affect weather patterns",
        "c": "how human activity contributes to ozone depletion",
        "d": "how greenhouse gas emissions contribute to global warming",
        "e": "how feedback loops amplify the effects of climate change",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Bert Bolin travel to discuss environmental issues in 1959?",
        "a": "Washington, D.C.",
        "b": "Paris",
        "c": "Berlin",
        "d": "Moscow",
        "e": "Beijing",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is the Keeling Curve important?",
        "a": "It proves that sea levels have risen considerably in recent years.",
        "b": "It assesses the effectiveness of conservation efforts.",
        "c": "It highlights the causes of the current climate crisis.",
        "d": "It tracks the impact of human activity on biodiversity.",
        "e": "It estimates the probability of a new extinction event.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the ICSU respond to emerging data about atmospheric carbon dioxide?",
        "a": "by creating a committee on atmospheric sciences",
        "b": "by issuing a statement urging government action",
        "c": "by organizing an international conference of scientists",
        "d": "by developing a global framework for addressing climate change",
        "e": "by proposing new carbon pricing policies",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following organizations helped establish the Global Atmospheric Research Program?",
        "a": "the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change",
        "b": "the American Meteorological Society",
        "c": "the United Nations Environmental Program",
        "d": "the World Meteorological Association",
        "e": "the National Aeronautics and Space Administration",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did GARP MOST greatly contribute to climate research?",
        "a": "the 1980s and 1990s",
        "b": "the 1940s and 1950s",
        "c": "the 1990s and 2000s",
        "d": "the 1970s and 1980s",
        "e": "the 1950s and 1960s",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the International Workshop on Climate Issues take place?",
        "a": "Belgium",
        "b": "Australia",
        "c": "Austria",
        "d": "Brazil",
        "e": "Japan",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did scientists create the World Climate Research Programme?",
        "a": "1975",
        "b": "1968",
        "c": "1971",
        "d": "1982",
        "e": "1979",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did scientists create the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme?",
        "a": "to foster international cooperation in addressing climate change",
        "b": "to evaluate the effectiveness of current research methods",
        "c": "to understand historical changes in climate patterns",
        "d": "to contextualize climate change and its causes",
        "e": "to develop strategies for sustainable resource allocation",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme differ from its predecessors?",
        "a": "It focused more on solving climate change than understanding it.",
        "b": "It studied climate change from a multidisciplinary perspective.",
        "c": "It studied climate change within an Earth System Science framework.",
        "d": "It integrated new digital technologies into its studies.",
        "e": "It emphasized the role of human activities in environmental changes.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which scientist helped push for the creation of the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme?",
        "a": "Charles David Keeling",
        "b": "Alessandra Korap Munduruku",
        "c": "Eugene F. Stoermer",
        "d": "Rachel Carson",
        "e": "Bert Bolin",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which main factor led to the creation of the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme?",
        "a": "the belief that more coordination was required between policymakers and scientists",
        "b": "the desire for a new scientific program to contextualize climate change and its causes",
        "c": "the growing global necessity for experienced climate scientists",
        "d": "the actions of the United States’ government during the de-escalation of the Cold War",
        "e": "awareness of the decreasing amounts of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what scientific framework did the International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme study global warming?",
        "a": "Earth system science",
        "b": "aerospace systems",
        "c": "biomedical systems",
        "d": "biochemistry systems",
        "e": "systems engineering",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1980s, climate scientists focused their efforts on",
        "a": "introducing global warming to government policymakers",
        "b": "identifying the primary greenhouse gas causing global warming",
        "c": "raising public awareness about global warming",
        "d": "discovering the causes of global warming",
        "e": "determining whether global temperatures were increasing",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did scientists agree upon in the 1985 conference Assessment of the Role of Carbon Dioxide and of Other Greenhouse Gases in Climate Variations and Associated Impacts?",
        "a": "that global warming was of lower concern",
        "b": "that government actions needed to be taken against global warming",
        "c": "that individuals were primarily at fault for global warming",
        "d": "that climate change arose from natural variability in solar energy",
        "e": "that greenhouse gas emissions could cause global warming",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization released a report that warned of the impacts of human actions on global warming directly after a 1985 conference on climate change?",
        "a": "Scientific Committee on Problems of the Environment",
        "b": "World Meteorological Organization",
        "c": "Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change",
        "d": "UN Environment Programme",
        "e": "George C. Marshall Institute",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Advisory Group on Greenhouse Gases was primarily formed as a(n)",
        "a": "source of research funding",
        "b": "international working group",
        "c": "grant-making organization",
        "d": "way to communicate scientific knowledge",
        "e": "educational task force",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1988 WMO conference entitled The Changing Atmosphere: Implications for Global Security was hosted in",
        "a": "Canada",
        "b": "Germany",
        "c": "Japan",
        "d": "France",
        "e": "Austria",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which NASA scientist testified before the United States Senate that human-caused greenhouse gas emissions were the cause of climate change?",
        "a": "James E. Hansen",
        "b": "Katherine Hayhoe",
        "c": "Eunice Newton Foote",
        "d": "Charles David Keeling",
        "e": "Erik M. Conway",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which decade did knowledge of climate change risks first spread widely?",
        "a": "1970s",
        "b": "1990s",
        "c": "1960s",
        "d": "2000s",
        "e": "1980s",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization was MOST influential in the spread of climate change science in the late 1980s?",
        "a": "United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change",
        "b": "Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change",
        "c": "George C. Marshall Institute",
        "d": "World Climate Research Programme",
        "e": "Global Atmospheric Research Program",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who served as the FIRST chair of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change?",
        "a": "Bert Bolin",
        "b": "Paul J. Crutzen",
        "c": "Charles David Keeling",
        "d": "James E. Hansen",
        "e": "Naomi Oreskes",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change was to",
        "a": "immediately halt all greenhouse gas emissions",
        "b": "further research on the causes of climate change",
        "c": "raise awareness about climate change",
        "d": "defend government actions regarding climate change",
        "e": "help scientists and policymakers communicate",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization is seen today as the MOST authoritative source of information about global warming and climate change?",
        "a": "Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change",
        "b": "Scripps Institute of Oceanography",
        "c": "Advisory Group on Greenhouse Gases",
        "d": "World Climate Research Programme",
        "e": "International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which decade featured the STRONGEST opposition to human involvement in global warming?",
        "a": "1960s",
        "b": "1970s",
        "c": "1990s",
        "d": "2000s",
        "e": "1980s",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    }
]
